<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on naxxfish</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/categories/personal/</link><description>software systems engineer, architect and product manager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Chris Roberts</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://naxxfish.net/categories/personal/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/hello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/hello/</guid><description>👋🏻 Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Chris.
I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer.
I believe in
Ethical, appropriate and sensible application of big data and ML. Taking a pragmatic approach to automated testing (test coverage isn&amp;rsquo;t everything). Designing systems that minimise carbon emissions and energy usage during their operational life. Being accountable for the products you build. Empowering users to achieve their goals, rather than mollycoddling them and making decisions for them. Harnessing creative chaos where it&amp;rsquo;s useful, but limiting it when it&amp;rsquo;s not.</description></item><item><title>A Crunchless Hackathon</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2022-08-09-crunchless-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2022-08-09-crunchless-hackathon/</guid><description>Hackathons or Hackdays or &amp;ldquo;Innovation Days&amp;rdquo; or whatever you want to call them have been a mainstay in tech for a while now. Sometimes, they&amp;rsquo;re seen as a simple &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; for an organisation that&amp;rsquo;s lacking innovation (spoiler: that&amp;rsquo;s not how they work). But, just so we&amp;rsquo;re all on the same page:
A Hackathon is a time limited sprint where (primarily) software is created
I&amp;rsquo;ve been purposely vauge here - but I think this definition encompasses most things that someone would call a &amp;ldquo;Hackathon&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>This is fine 🔥 (no, it's not)</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2022-07-20-on-fire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2022-07-20-on-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a staunch advocate of &lt;a href="https://naxxfish.net/affordable-sustainability-2021/">sustainability&lt;/a>. Being an engineer, I make things - and one of my life goals is for everything I build to use as little energy (and therefore carbon emissions) as possible. Because, in my view, I can contribute to limiting climate change, even in a small way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week, the UK has seen the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/jul/20/heatwave-led-to-london-firefighters-busiest-day-since-second-world-war">hottest temperatures in recorded history&lt;/a>. All of our infrastructure experienced failures - roads, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2022/jul/20/britains-rail-services-severely-disrupted-as-heatwave-damage-is-repaired">railways&lt;/a>, electricity grids. There were droughts, and the firefighters were busier than they have ever been since World War 2. Our homes are &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-62179678">ill equipped for these kinds of temperatures&lt;/a> and this will cost lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most news outlets were quite clear: this heatwave is a direct result of climate change. The Sun and the Daily Express gave it a different spin - we&amp;rsquo;re all getting a free holiday right on our doorstep! Hooray! 🙄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is everyone going to build the Metaverse?</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2021-11-29-everyones-building-a-metaverse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2021-11-29-everyones-building-a-metaverse/</guid><description>Ever since Meta (nee Facebook) announced their intention of building &amp;ldquo;the Metaverse&amp;rdquo; in their Facebook Connect conference keynote in 2021, changing their name in the process - the world has been simultaneously enthrealled, amused and terrified by the idea of spending more of their time in a virtual world rather than the real one.
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because they remember the dystopian setting of Ready Player One, where people live in towering stacks of containers because their cities have become uninhabitable due to overcrowding and energy shortages are commonplace - and the only way to escape is through the OASIS &amp;ldquo;metaverse&amp;rdquo; - leading them to neglect to fix the problems with physical society in preference to enjoying a virtual one instead.</description></item><item><title>Crowdfunding Witch-hunt: Debunking Debunks of Aurora Nutrio</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2021-04-18-crowdfunding-witchhunt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/posts/2021-04-18-crowdfunding-witchhunt/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many moons ago, I was a host on a podcast called The Gadget Crowd.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="TGC-coverart.jpg" alt="I&amp;amp;rsquo;m the guy on the far left, raising my eyebrow">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My role was to do the deep dives into the technical feasibility of the projects that we talked about - usually tempering the hyperbolic claims of the campaigns into something more realistic. I also featured a number of exceptionally bizarre campaigns claiming everything from a perpetual motion machine powered by demonic forces (legitimately what the project claimed), to a device that was designed to release your inner &lt;em>chi&lt;/em> by regularly beeping (who&amp;rsquo;s campaign text read much like the incoherent ramblings of someone with severe psychosis).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, many crowdfunded tech projects have come and gone, and the public has now experienced a range of outcomes from great success (for example the &lt;a href="https://www.riut.co.uk/">RiutBag&lt;/a>, which delivered exactly as intended and is a ongoing business delivering new, useful, products regularly), to great failures (like &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/sep/01/juicero-silicon-valley-shutting-down">Juicero&lt;/a> - which was a legitimate, but dumb, idea that just failed), to outright scams (like &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1041610927/znaps-the-9-magnetic-adapter-for-your-mobile-devic/description">ZNAPS&lt;/a> - where backers have now resorted to magic incantations trying to get their money back). The general public has seen it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward a few (&lt;em>cough&lt;/em> five) years, and there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/shittykickstarters/">/r/shittykickstarters&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let me say, most of the posts on this subreddit are legitimately bad campaigns - which are either unfeasible, physically impossible or in some other way questionable (e.g. rebrands of products available from contract manufacturers). But sometimes, those redditors are a bit too ready to take up their pitchfork&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take this one, &lt;a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/aurora-nutrio-the-easiest-way-to-track-food/x/19988273#/">Aurora Nutrio&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sustainability: An affordable future?</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/affordable-sustainability-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/affordable-sustainability-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>I found myself looking for a better option for tying my hair up in a ponytail. It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for over a decade, and isn&amp;rsquo;t likely to change soon. But the ties I&amp;rsquo;ve been buying keep breaking - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what I do, they just get looser and looser until they don&amp;rsquo;t hold my hair properly, and then they snap. So I started looking for reusable, robust products designed to fulfil this purpose, and I came across &lt;a href="https://www.tabithaeve.co.uk/products/nobbles-plastic-free-hair-ties">these hair ties from Tabitha Eve&lt;/a>. They come in a pack of 5, and their RRP is &lt;strong>£10&lt;/strong> (although they&amp;rsquo;re on sale for £6 currently). The ones I get normally are about £3 for a pack of 18 from Superdrug.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This prompted a train of thought - as much as I support sustainable and ethical consumerism - is the hope that one day all consumers will be ethical consumers completely detatched from reality?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WhatsApp Migration</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/whatsapp-keychange/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/whatsapp-keychange/</guid><description>Hello! You might have found this because I&amp;rsquo;ve sent you a message saying that I&amp;rsquo;m moving phone 📱
This is in fact true! On the 5th July, 2020, I have got a new phone.
If you have a WhatsApp chat with me going, it will say that my encryption key 🔑 has been changed. This is a normal thing to happen when setting up a new app on a new phone - doing so has meant that I&amp;rsquo;ve had to re-verify my phone number as well.</description></item><item><title>Pwnage While-U-Wait: Migrating WhatsApp messages between Android and iOS</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/whatsapp-android-to-iphone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 22:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/whatsapp-android-to-iphone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I made the (somewhat contraversial) decision to move from Android to iOS. And whilst for the most part this process has been polished to a high sheen by Apple, desperate to make the transition frictionless, there are a few notable gaps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of those, is WhatsApp message history - which is not possible to port between OSes. This missing feature has unintentionally spawned a plethora of questionable third party software solutions, and some even more questionable marketing techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explore why the problem exists, why it&amp;rsquo;s not easily solved, and the &amp;ldquo;opportunity&amp;rdquo; that these software providers are exploiting, and perhaps the people too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remote ID and Drones</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2020/03/08/remote-id-and-drones/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2020/03/08/remote-id-and-drones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Drone safety is a topic which has had particular interest after &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-47919680">recent incidents&lt;/a>. Whilst there have yet to be any cases of a drone actually colliding with an aircraft, there&amp;rsquo;s a definitely feeling there is a percieved risk of this occurring - which is sufficient that seeing a drone anywhere near close to an airport will immediately cause mass chaos as the entire airport is grounded until it has been removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With tech giants like Amazon developing automated drone-delivery systems, the number of drones in the skies is likely to increase - and obviously law-makers are being pressured to make sure that this is a safe future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Photography Workflow</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2019/12/08/my-photography-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2019/12/08/my-photography-workflow/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://naxxfish.photography">I make photographs&lt;/a> in my spare time. Although often they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;a href="https://naxxfish.net/2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/">on film&lt;/a>, but as part of my hybrid workflow they almost always end up going through a digital process at some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post explains how I manage my photos from capture to archive, and how I manage backups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🗒 Sharing notes between Joplin users</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/sharing-notes-joplin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/sharing-notes-joplin/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I mentioned in a &lt;a href="https://naxxfish.net/note-taking-apps-for-engineers-2019">previous post&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move to &lt;a href="https://www.joplinapp.org/">Joplin&lt;/a> for my note taking needs. One of the last features I was missing was the ability for me to share a note with other people - as I do with Google Keep at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one missing this feature, &lt;a href="https://discourse.joplinapp.org/t/sharing-notes-or-notebooks/67/38">there&amp;rsquo;s a thread on the forum&lt;/a> requesting this that&amp;rsquo;s been open for a long time, and has a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of views. So I decided to try and help develop it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Note-taking apps for Engineers in 2019</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/note-taking-apps-for-engineers-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/note-taking-apps-for-engineers-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>Up until now, notes that I make for work and personal purposes are scattered across a bunch of different places in an un-searchable, un-maintainable, mess. I decided enough was enough and I should do something about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at what options are available for cross-platform notes, preferably that support &lt;a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/">Markdown&lt;/a> and are open-source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Only Way is Ethics</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2019/03/10/the-only-way-is-ethics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 21:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2019/03/10/the-only-way-is-ethics/</guid><description>Recently I was talking to someone in a pub, and mentioned that I engaged in film photography. They mentioned that they did not personally approve of film photography, as it contains animal products.
This is not something I had previously put much thought into, despite generally agreeing that meat is not a particularly sustainable source of food. Whilst, after a bit of research, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly at peace with the fact that photographic emulsion uses an extremely small amount of gelatin – primarily as it is making use of a by-product which otherwise would have gone to waste, and in of itself isn&amp;rsquo;t a driver for meat production.</description></item><item><title>Wish List</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/wish-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 16:44:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/wish-list/</guid><description>For a long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Amazon Wishlist to help people figure out what sort of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to be given as a present. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that isn&amp;rsquo;t a particularly great solution, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give people the choice of retailer – especially where there is a local one they could support instead.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve made my own Wishlist containing a bunch of things that I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate, which is hosted by GitHub pages, using some code by ndarville to render a nice wishlist template using Jekyll.</description></item><item><title>You’re lacing your shoelaces wrong</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2018/10/20/youre-doing-your-shoelaces-wrong/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2018/10/20/youre-doing-your-shoelaces-wrong/</guid><description>In this world of Trump, Brexit and Fake News, you may well be wondering to yourself:
How can I trust anything I used to take for granted any more? I thought I generally had a grip on these things, but maybe not! What else am I taking for granted that&amp;rsquo;s completely wrong? Am I getting out of bed properly? Am I competent to make the journey from home to work? Are my shoes laced up properly?</description></item><item><title>Why I Shoot Film in 2018 📷</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 08:30:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="center" >
&lt;img
sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw"
srcset='
/2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/phonebox_hu33b94e7e976bab8388b4dc965b54afb2_143389_500x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 500w
, /2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/phonebox_hu33b94e7e976bab8388b4dc965b54afb2_143389_800x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 800w
'
src="https://naxxfish.net/2018/09/01/why-i-shoot-film-in-2018/phonebox_hu33b94e7e976bab8388b4dc965b54afb2_143389_1200x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
alt="">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;a href="http://naxxfish.photography">Photography&lt;/a> is one of my (numerous and disparate) hobbies, and you may be perplexed to learn that I shoot quite a lot of 35mm film. Can you even do that any more? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that really inconvenient?  As it turns out, yes on both counts, but I quite enjoy it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have always been interested in documenting the world around me, and I was given a Nikon F-301 (35mm film SLR) camera as a teenager to learn with.  Almost from the start, I was what might be termed an “aspiring” photographer – more serious than your average “holiday snapper”, and not a professional, but always wanting to improve my skills and images.  I was rarely happy with taking the odd snapshot here and there and was always looking out for opportunities to record how I saw the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is how it came to be…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Headphones</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2018/06/26/my-headphones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 22:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2018/06/26/my-headphones/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="center" >
&lt;img
sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw"
srcset='
/2018/06/26/my-headphones/IMG_0834_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_72497_500x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 500w
, /2018/06/26/my-headphones/IMG_0834_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_72497_800x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 800w
'
src="https://naxxfish.net/2018/06/26/my-headphones/IMG_0834_hu5438825b9b6d1014226d20d231e650c2_72497_1200x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
alt="">
&lt;/figure>
As someone who works in audio, I appreciate a good quality set of headphones.  I am, by no means, an audiophile – I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer. I want my products to operate within tolerances that are suitable for their purpose – I&amp;rsquo;m not up for cryogenically &lt;a href="https://mniec.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/snake-oil-of-the-year-award-audiophile-cables/">freezing my cables&lt;/a> or painting my &lt;a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/bewaring-of-the-green/">CDs with green pen,&lt;/a> or indeed any other magical tweaks to get marginal gains, at best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I do want something that will serve me well, and be comfortable doing so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🗺️ Recording GPS Tracks with GPSlogger on Android for Realtime Trains 🚆</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 22:04:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img
sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw"
srcset='
/2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/20170918_171158_huc63b1c60aa7e305e911423a40b3e3201_144846_500x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 500w
, /2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/20170918_171158_huc63b1c60aa7e305e911423a40b3e3201_144846_800x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 800w
, /2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/20170918_171158_huc63b1c60aa7e305e911423a40b3e3201_144846_1200x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1200w
'
src="https://naxxfish.net/2018/03/14/recording-gps-tracks-with-gpslogger-on-android-for-realtime-trains/20170918_171158_huc63b1c60aa7e305e911423a40b3e3201_144846_1200x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
alt="">
&lt;figcaption class="center" >A Class 800 test train set spotted at Paddington shortly before the launch of the Intercity 125 replacements in October 2017, operated by GWR and Virgin East Coast&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>As a long time user of &lt;a href="http://www.realtimetrains.co.uk/">Realtimetrains.co.uk&lt;/a> (which is where you should go for all your real time train tracking needs in the UK), and someone with an appreciation of Open Rail Data (having &lt;a href="https://github.com/naxxfish/nrod-funnel">used it myself&lt;/a>), I jumped at the chance of helping their development.  They&amp;rsquo;ve put out an appeal to &lt;a href="http://www.realtimetrains.co.uk/tracks/">record GPS tracks&lt;/a> of train services that you travel on with the link to the service on the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A lot of the work behind the scenes performed by a small team involves maintaining data relating to train positioning and comparing this with the signalling system outputs we use. This is an entirely manual task involving one of us going out with a radio controlled watch and monitoring the passage of trains through stations and junctions. An area of recent interest for us has been attempting to compute this automatically using other known bits of information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to validate this effort, we either have to do the manual task with a watch or collect a large dataset of GPS traces to compare against our dataset. The more data we have will allow us to improve the end product.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which is awesome.  I wanted to contribute. I found a suitable app for Android called &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mendhak.gpslogger">GPSlogger&lt;/a> which seemed to fit the bill.  It has quite a few settings, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick guide on what I&amp;rsquo;ve used to successfully generate a working track for a service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I don’t want a Yahoo ID any more</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2015/10/30/why-i-dont-want-a-yahoo-id-any-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 13:11:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2015/10/30/why-i-dont-want-a-yahoo-id-any-more/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was at one time, a BT customer.  They had the best deal for FTTC broadband in my area, so it made sense to go with them.  One of the things they offered at the time was a Yahoo account – which for some inexplicable reason you were forced to link to any previous account with the same email address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created one – with my usual online moniker of naxxfish.  What a mistake that turned out to be….&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CanterburyMedia Site to Site Link</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2014/10/02/canterburymedia-site-to-site-link/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 11:36:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2014/10/02/canterburymedia-site-to-site-link/</guid><description>One of the unique challenges of CSR FMis it&amp;rsquo;s structure, where it is part funded by two separate universities each with a presence in Canterbury (University of Kent and Christ Church University) and their respective student unions (Kent Union and CCCU). Student members could be enrolled at either institution, and as such each institution has it&amp;rsquo;s own radio studio on campus – each of which has an equal chance of being put on air.</description></item><item><title>Keynestock 2014</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2014/06/02/keynestock-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 08:55:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2014/06/02/keynestock-2014/</guid><description>Once again, I got roped into helping out CSRfm and this time KTV in getting their OBs from Keynstock 2014 on air.
There were some not insignficant challenges. Our normal network access at Keynes was effectively cut off due to some changes to configuration. This was quite troublesome, as we had always previously relied on this access to get our signals back to our HQ. The outlook seemed bleak. What we ended up doing instead, though, actually seemed to work out rather better.</description></item><item><title>PathfinderPC HTTP JSON API</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2014/03/19/pathfinderpc-http-json-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:30:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2014/03/19/pathfinderpc-http-json-api/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping with the installation of a brand new Axia Livewire network at CSR FM. We&amp;rsquo;ve been using PathfinderPC to do all of the routing control.
It&amp;rsquo;s all pretty clever stuff — but we wanted to be able to extract information from Pathfinder so that we could do handy things like find out which studio is on air, and use that information to show the right webcam on the website, or use it to add further information to our Now Playing data.</description></item><item><title>Betheremin 0.1</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/2014/02/02/betheremin-0-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 18:54:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/2014/02/02/betheremin-0-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>My partner, Beth, asked me if I could make her a Theremin.  So I have.  It&amp;rsquo;s called the Betheremin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theremin">Theremin&lt;/a> is a musical instrument, which changes pitch and/or volume as you bring your hand close to it&amp;rsquo;s antenna(e).  The way this works is by your hand influencing the capacitance of a resonator circuit, changing the frequency at which it oscillates.  This difference in frequency creates a “beat” frequency against a reference oscillator, which can then be used to create an audible frequency or control a Voltage Controlled Amplifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>about</title><link>https://naxxfish.net/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 21:11:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naxxfish.net/about/</guid><description>👋🏻 Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Chris.
Nice to meet you! I&amp;rsquo;m from London, UK – which is where I presently live. I work for Media Molecule.
I&amp;rsquo;m a photographer, and have published a series of zines about phone boxes.
I code for a living.
I sometimes build electronics for fun.
I hold a UK Amateur Radio Operator License, callsign M7NXF.
I&amp;rsquo;m the owner of both a beard, and a ponytail.
You&amp;rsquo;d ordinarily frequently find me at An Evening of Unnecessary Detail.</description></item></channel></rss>